Teodor Fratiloiu

teodor.fratiloiu@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/teodor-fratiloiu

UK HPI visa holder, EU citizen. Recent graduate of the Technical University of Munich with a MS degree in Electrical Engineering. Specialized in ML and cybersecurity, with a strong interest in the intersection of these fields. During my studies, I gained 2 years of work experience in a hyper-growth environment (5x team-level, 3x company growth) at Celonis, Germany's and New York's highest valued startup. Furthermore, I have lab and thesis project experience with machine learning, including model design and data pipelines.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Information Security Analyst – Celonis (Munich), Part-time

Dec 2020 – Feb 2023

- Performed gap assessments to harmonize controls across new and existing cybersecurity frameworks;
 automated the collection of evidence for continuous compliance with ISO 27001 and SOC 2.
- Helped author and test BC/DR plans for EMEA and NA entities, conferred with stakeholders to account for critical data assets in 2 enterprise SaaS products hosted in a multi-cloud environment.
- Assisted with developing information security policies, standard operating procedures, and corporate training material, including the management of automated phishing training for the entire organization.
- Periodically reviewed access rights to cloud systems with up to 6-digit user counts; cross-queried databases to ensure appropriateness; assessed the physical security of premises.

Student Assistant – *Introductory Information Security Courses at TUM*

May 2020 – Jan 2021

• Prepared lab content for students, explained solutions and hosted educational videos. Assisted the rest of the teaching staff during live remote classes for students in Munich and Singapore.

Member and Mentor – adveisor (Technical University of Munich)

Oct 2018 – Jun 2019

 Participated in a soft-skills and personal development programme with outside, professional coaching, including multiple 3-5 day offsite training sessions. Applied the acquired knowledge by hosting 10 project management workshops during my second year of university for "mentee" freshers.

EDUCATION

Technical University of Munich (TUM) - Graduated

M.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

2020 - 2023

Areas of focus: Machine Learning, Information Security and Automation

Thesis title: Peeking Into the Decision-Making Process in the Human Mind via DL Models

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

2017 - 2020

Thesis about compressing ML models to fit on embedded devices (memory & compute constraints).

SKILLS

Languages English, German, Romanian

Coding Python, C (incl. embedded), C++ (incl. HPC), JS/TS

Frameworks TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, React, Node.js, Docker, Git, Linux

Security ISO 27001, SOC 2, NIST, OWASP